<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software engineer on eikcaj sweet</title>
    <link>https://eikkaj.github.io/tags/software-engineer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software engineer on eikcaj sweet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eikkaj.github.io/tags/software-engineer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to search for documents via their parent containers (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2021-05-05-searchingviacontainersp2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2021-05-05-searchingviacontainersp2/</guid>
      <description>I wrote an article a couple of weeks ago about searching for documents via their parent containers and provided some code samples for a custom ElasticSearch Writer that would help facilitate that. As I previously explained, a document holds a relationship with its parent via the OOTB property ecm:parentId. If I were to add ecm:parentId as a predicate to a page provider and scaffold the search layouts in Designer, Studio would add a standard textfield in the search form that users could utilize to search via the ecm:parentId.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to select all documents from search and send to bulk action</title>
      <link>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2021-04-28-selectallbulk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2021-04-28-selectallbulk/</guid>
      <description>Hey all, I was recently asked what the best way was to implement a &amp;ldquo;Select All&amp;rdquo; type of functionality in the Nuxeo Web UI such that all documents returned in a search could be sent to a particular bulk action. This is actually something on the Nuxeo roadmap to be implemented officially, but meanwhile, I figured I&amp;rsquo;d show a quick workaround. Select All currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist because of the challenges around selecting all of the checkboxes in the results view when it is a lazily load infinite scrolling list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to search for documents via their parent containers</title>
      <link>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2021-04-21-searchingviacontainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2021-04-21-searchingviacontainers/</guid>
      <description>Hey all, I was recently asked what the best way is to created a page provider / search in the Nuxeo WebUI that allows users to search for documents and filter by their parent containers. I thought this was a great opportunity to create a sandbox project with some code that folks can adapt and utilize.
Check out the git repo for searching via parent containers
The solution I am proposing requires some Studio configuration and java development, and this is due to the nature of Nuxeo&amp;rsquo;s OOTB data model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Docker in a Dev Environment with Nuxeo</title>
      <link>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2021-04-14-nuxeodocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2021-04-14-nuxeodocker/</guid>
      <description>Hey all, this will be the first post of a series of posts related to working with Nuxeo as a developer while utilizing Docker.
As a long time Nuxeo developer, I&amp;rsquo;ve run Nuxeo across a lot of different mediums, including an attempt on an old RPI once, but that&amp;rsquo;s for another blog post at a future date. Admittedly, for the vast majority of my tenure at Nuxeo, I haven&amp;rsquo;t worked all that much with our Docker images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2014-3-3-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eikkaj.github.io/posts/2014-3-3-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting semi-regularly about tech related things that I am interested in, particularly related to Nuxeo. I&amp;rsquo;d love to collaborate and also welcome feedback. My contact info can be found in the About page. Cheers!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
